Take the lab rat,
以小鼠
no,
不对
the roast chicken.
烧鸡
Take the roast chicken and locate
以烧鸡两骸旁
the midpoint of the front line of the upper spine as the center line.
上脊前线中点作为中线
Five millimeters to the left of the center line,
中线向左五毫米的地方
we bluntly separate the subcutaneous tissue...
钝性分离皮下组织
And paravertebral muscles.
和椎旁肌肉
How about that?
怎么样 姐妹们
A whole morning of experiments on lab rats
一上午的小鼠实验
is not a waste of time, is it?
没白练吧
Yes, it is.
白练了
Can you say something I like to hear instead?
说点姐爱听的好吧
Say,
你说
Gu Chen was doing great
顾晨在以前实验室
in his previous lab,
干得好好的
why did he suddenly transfer
为什么突然转到
to your lab?
你们实验室呢
He said that he's more interested in
他说杜专家的研究方向
Du Zhuanjia's research fields.
他更感兴趣
It's but an excuse.
这都是借口
Gu Chen's GPA is 4.9.
顾晨的绩点有四点九
He'll be accepted by any lab
他想去哪个实验室
if he applies, right?
他去不了啊 对不对
Right.
对了
Moreover,
再说了
if he's so interested in
他要真对杜老师的实验
Prof. Du's experiments,
那么感兴趣
why didn't he apply
他最开始的时候
at the beginning?
为什么不去呢
Am I right?
是不是
Yes.
是
Yes, you are.
没错
What do you mean?
你们什么意思
Say,
你说
is there any possibility that Gu Chen is
顾晨会不会
into you?
对你有意思啊
He knew that you are not happy
他看你在肖宇河那儿
working at Xiao Yuhe's place,
干得不开心
so he discreetly and deliberately
所以偷偷故意
transferred here to lend you a hand.
转过来帮你
Be realistic.
大姐
When I bought allergy medications
当时我给肖宇河
and a jacket
买过敏药
for Xiao Yuhe,
还有外套的时候
it was Gu Chen who kept me company.
就是顾晨陪着我去的
He knows that I have a crush on Xiao Yuhe.
他知道我喜欢肖宇河
Then that's even more telling.
那就更说明问题了
Previously,
之前
he knew that you have a crush on someone,
他知道你有喜欢的人
so he cannot do much
所以没办法
other than supporting you
只能在背后
silently from behind.
默默地支持你
But now it's different.
可是现在不一样了
The situation has changed.
情况有变
Instead of supporting in silence,
他决定不再沉默
he decides to step in.
挺身而出
In.
而出
Li Meizi,
李梅子
look at me.
你看看我
I'm all hurt and broken.
已经是千疮百孔了
Any teeny-weeny
再有那么一点点
trivial stuff
微不足道的小事情
can be my last straw.
我就立马死机重启
Just let me be,
放过我吧
please.
好吗
Hurry up and eat.
赶紧吃饭
Then I'll head to the lab.
吃完饭我去实验室了
They are a... a...
他们两个配 配
a match made in heaven.
天仙配
OK, we've done messing around.
好 不闹不闹不闹
Let's dig in.
吃饭吃饭吃饭
Look.
你看
The clubs are full of handsome boys.
社团里有好多帅哥
They are recruiting new members recently.
最近正在社团招新
We should drop by and have a look later.
我们等会儿过去看看
Hurry and eat.
快吃快吃
Hello,
同学
can I interest you in the Ping Pong Club?
来乒乓球社了解一下
A hit on the ball, and you'll be the best of all.
乒乒乓乓天下无双
Hello,
同学
can I interest you in the Street Dance Club?
街舞社了解一下
I... I'll take a look at the Ping Pong Club.
我去 我去看乒乓球了
Then I'll take a look over there.
那我去那边看看
Later.
走走走
Chengcheng,
澄澄
you are interested in calligraphy?
你对书法还感兴趣呢
I... I'm just browsing around.
我我 我随便看看的
You are also trying to join a club?
你也来 看社团
Yes, I'm still choosing.
对啊 还在选
Is there any possibility that Gu Chen's
顾晨会不会
into you?
对你有意思啊
He knew that you are not happy
他看你在肖宇河那儿
working at Xiao Yuhe's place,
干得不开心
so he discreetly and deliberately
所以偷偷故意
transferred here to lend you a hand.
转过来帮你
Then I suppose you have already
那你明天大物作业
finished the physics assignment that's due tomorrow.
应该做完了吧
Have you picked a topic?
课题选好了吗
Not yet.
还没有
It's due tomorrow.
明天就要交了
How about this.
这样吧
You hurry up and pick one today,
你今天快点选
and I'll ask the professor tomorrow
明天我给老师说一下
to give our class one more day.
我们班后天交
Thank you, monitor.
谢谢你啊 班长
I'll go and find Meizi, then.
那我去找梅子了
OK.
好 去吧
Are you alright?
你没事吧
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Xixi.
西溪姐
Could you take a look at
你能不能帮我看一下
my design and see
我这个设计
if there's something wrong with it?
是不是有什么问题呀
Your design is
你这是一个
an experiment for long-term monitoring
小鼠大脑神经元
of lab rats' brain neuronal activity.
长期监测的实验
Electrodes are implanted for up to one year.
电极植入时间长达一年
Now, you are using a
你现在用的是一个
Utah Electrode Array.
尤他阵列电极
It will cause immune responses
这个电极注入时间长了
when implanted for too long,
会产生免疫反应
which will lead to failure.
导致失效
In the end, the functioning time will only be a few months.
最后有效期只剩几个月
You should change it into
你应该换成一个
nano-mesh electrodes.
纳米网状电极
OK.
行
Thank you, Xixi.
谢谢西溪姐
Wait, Xixi,
对了 溪姐
do you have any time available in the next two days?
你这两天有空吗
I want to treat you to dinner.
我请你吃饭
You have time for dinner,
有时间吃饭
but you don't have time for your thesis?
没时间写论文吗
If you don't submit it tomorrow,
明天再不交
you'll be doomed.
死定了你
I will. I will.
交 交
Thank you, Xixi.
谢谢西溪姐
Xixi,
溪姐
why are today's chips all coriander flavored?
今天怎么全是香菜味的
Who bought these?
这谁买的
They were all purchased by Gu Chen.
这都是顾晨买的
By Gu Chen?
顾晨买的
Xixi, Dongmao.
西溪师姐 东茂师兄
Both of you are here.
都在呢
Gu Chen.
顾晨
Do you also like
你也喜欢吃
coriander flavored chips?
香菜味的薯片
Didn't you
上次师姐
give me a bag of coriander flavored chips last time?
你不是给了我一包吗
I found it tasty.
我觉得味道还不错
So I bought some more.
就又买了点
Right, Xixi.
对了师姐
How's your study
你那个
on how to use steady-state visual evoked potentials (SSVEP)
稳态视觉诱发电位
to locate retinopathy cells
对视网膜病变细胞的
coming along?
定位进展得怎么样了
It's still processing.
那个还在推进
I'm going to study more about it
我准备今天晚上回家
tonight.
再研究研究
This flavor tastes awful.
这个味道太难吃了
Fortunately,
还好不是
I didn't pay for it myself.
我自己花钱买的
What tastes so awful?
吃什么这么难吃
Coriander flavored chips.
香菜风味的薯片
Coriander flavored?
香菜味
Why are you eating
你吃张西溪的东西
Zhang Xixi's stuff?
干什么
It's not her purchase.
不是溪姐的
Gu Chen bought it.
顾晨买的
There are plenty of these in the lounge.
休息室买了一堆呢
I can fetch one for you.
我给你拿一包啊
No, I'm good.
我不吃
Here, try one.
来 试一下
No.
不吃
Who bought it?
你刚说谁买的
Gu Chen.
顾晨哪
This dog cafe
这家狗咖
is trending on social media.
可是一家网红店
It's very difficult to book a table.
真的特别难约
But of course,
当然了
all our consumption
我们今日所有的消费
will be paid for by Ms. Li.
都是由李总买单
Cheers.
干杯
I want a snap too.
我也拍张
I'm gonna post it on Moments.
我也要发朋友圈
This is delicious.
这个好吃
Too sweet.
甜
It's fine.
还好
Good grief.
天哪
Did you check your Moments?
你们看朋友圈了吗
Who did Gu Chen
顾晨这是跟谁
make the romantic gestures for?
隔空示爱呢
It's not something he normally would do.
不像他风格啊
Take a look.
你看
Let me see.
我看看
"Dragons should hide in clouds."
龙应当藏在云里
I know this one.
这我可知道
It's from The Scenery under Moon by Shen Congwen.
这是沈从文的月下小景
The next sentence is
下一句是
"You should hide in my heart."
你应当藏在心里
Gee.
天哪
Gu Chen has a crush on someone.
顾晨有喜欢的人了
I should gossip about this.
我应该八卦一下
How come I can't see this?
我怎么看不见啊
How come you can't...
你怎么看
Gimme. Lemme see. Hurry.
给我 给我看看 快
Why can't you see this post?
你怎么没有啊
Can you all see it?
你们有吗
Yes, of course.
有啊
We all can see it.
都有啊
Let me think.
让我想一想
No way.
不会吧
You can't be the heroine
顾晨说的女主角
Gu Chen's talking about.
不会就是你吧
You are his crush.
你就是他的心上人吧
He's too shy about it,
他觉得不好意思
so he blocked you on this post.
所以把你给屏蔽了
It's impossible.
怎么可能
Maybe Gu Chen
顾晨他说不定
blocks me entirely.
是所有朋友圈都屏蔽我
Lemme see.
你给我看看
See for yourself.
你看 你自己看
It's just this one post that's hidden from you.
就这一条没有
Right?
是不是
What do you think?
你们觉得呢
Does Gu Chen like Su Chengcheng?
是不是顾晨喜欢苏澄澄
Good for you, Chengcheng.
挺好的呀 澄澄
I heard that Gu Chen
我听说顾晨
grew up in a wealthy family.
家里条件挺好的
He bought his own house
高中的时候
when he was in high school.
人可把房都买了
I also think Gu Chen is a decent choice.
我也觉得顾晨挺好的
He's more suitable for you than Xiao Yuhe.
他比肖宇河要适合你
See?
你看
Even Bro Ying, who's always silent in discussions,
平时不参与话题的颖哥
spoke up.
都说话了
What do you think?
怎么样 你觉得呢
But,
可是
the person I have a crush on is not Gu Chen.
我喜欢的人又不是顾晨
What did you say?
你说什么
What did I say?
我说什么
I mean we are just
我说我跟顾晨
good friends.
就是好朋友
I'm pretty sure he only sees me as a friend.
人家肯定只拿我当朋友
Don't overthink this.
你别瞎想了
Let's give this post a like.
点个赞
Don't you enjoy
你不是喜欢喝
coriander flavored beverages?
香菜味的饮料吗
What are you trying to say?
你想说什么
Since you are Su Chengcheng's friend,
你既然是苏澄澄的朋友
you should stay in the friend zone.
你就待在朋友的位置
Chengcheng,
澄澄
did you finish retrieving the equipment?
你去取设备回来了吗
When are you heading back to the dorm?
啥时候回宿舍
Moreover, did Gu Chen contact you?
还有 顾晨联系你了吗
I reckon he's going to
我推断他这两天
confess his feelings to you in two days.
肯定会跟你表白
You'd better prepare for that.
你做好心理准备
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Let me help you.
我来帮你搬吧
This is too heavy.
这个太重了
Chengcheng, do you have a moment?
澄澄你有空吗
I have something to tell you.
我有话要对你说
I'm busy at the moment. I need to
我没有空 我要把东西
return the stuff to the laboratory.
还到实验室去
I'm all tied up.
我忙得很
Well, then, what about tonight?
那 那你今晚有空吗
The night's already taken, too.
我今晚也没空
OK, it's alright.
行 那没关系
I'll tell you another day.
我改天跟你说
Then it would be better if you tell me tonight.
那你还是今天晚上说吧
OK.
好
Let's meet at the garden at nine.
那我们九点小花园见
The garden?
小花园
Why are you here?
你怎么来了
As soon as I saw you borrow the card from Zhang Li,
我看到你跟张力借卡
I knew something was off.
就觉得有问题
Now you even left the door unlocked.
现在门都不锁了
You are so confident about not being caught, aren't you?
这么不怕被发现
What's the matter?
什么事
Du asked me to talk some sense into you.
老杜让我来劝劝你
If that's the case, you can go back now.
那你可以回去了
I figured that you wouldn't listen.
猜到你不会听劝
If you did, then you wouldn't be Xiao Yuhe.
听劝就不是肖宇河了
Don't beat around the bush, get to the point.
有话直接说
The development of Musk needs the knowledge of
马斯克开发需要用到
algorithm,
算法
psychology,
心理学
mechanics,
机械
all those subjects.
多个方面的学科
Even if you are a prodigy,
就算你是个天才
don't you realize
但是你觉得
it would be
没有人帮你
too difficult to complete
靠你一个人
without any help?
你做得过来吗
I already acknowledge all these problems
你说的这些问题
you mentioned,
我都知道
and I can solve them.
而且我都能解决
I've already fed Musk
马斯克已经让我喂了
plenty of data.
很多数据了
It's in the
已经到了
reinforcement learning stage.
强化学习的阶段
There's no need to worry.
不用担心
Everything's fine.
没问题
You know for yourself that
你自己也知道
Musk needs a large amount of
马斯克需要大量的
data on human emotional representations
人体情感表征的数据
in order to accurately correspond to
才能准确地对应
the mapping relationship of
外在表象
external appearances
和内在情感特征的
and internal emotional characteristics.
映射关系
Who's its current learning sample?
它现在学习样本是谁呀
Who does it interact with every day?
每天跟谁互动
It's only you, right?
是不是只有你一个人
You set Musk
你对马斯克的定位
as an
是一个
emotional companion robot.
情感陪护型的机器人
But you yourself
可是你自己呢
are a person with avoidant attachment style.
回避型依恋人格
Do you think you can train it well?
你觉得你训练得好它吗
I know I am
我知道我自己是
a person with avoidant attachment style.
回避型依恋人格
It's hard for me to be aware
很难察觉到
of my true feelings,
自己的真实感受
and it's even harder to directly express
更难直接表达出
my feelings,
自己的感受
which results in contrasting
导致行为和想法
behaviors and thoughts.
截然不同
If someone
如果对方
makes me feel stressful,
让我感觉到压力
I'll instinctively choose to avoid them.
我会本能地选择回避
This will indeed become
这确实是能成为马斯克
the greatest obstacle of Musk's training.
最大的训练障碍
But I'll overcome it.
但我会克服它
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河
you've changed.
你变了
Did Du tell you
老杜跟你说
about the lab?
实验室的事了吗
What's the matter?
什么事啊
Our school hosts an assessment
咱们学校每三年
every three years.
都有一次测评
This year is when it takes place.
正好到今年了
Our lab
咱们实验室呢
has been doing basic research
这几年
these recent years,
一直在做基础研究
and we haven't reached much of an achievement.
没有什么成果
So if we cannot
所以如果今年
pass the assessment this year,
考评不通过
our lab
咱们实验室
might exist no more.
可能就没有了
What do you mean our lab might exist no more?
什么叫实验室没有了
It might get relegated,
就是降级
then split and merged with other labs.
然后拆分兼并
Du's been distressed lately,
老杜最近一直都很焦虑
but he doesn't want us to feel pressured,
但是他不想给咱们压力
so he said nothing about it.
所以一直没往外说
I know Musk
我知道马斯克
means a lot to you.
对你的意义很大
I'm not Du,
我不是老杜
I think it's perfectly fine
你做自己想做的事情
for you to do what you want to do.
我觉得完全没问题
But I also want you to know that
但是我也希望你知道
you are a member of our lab.
你 是实验室的一份子
You must carry the responsibility
该你扛的责任
assigned to you.
你必须要扛起来
I understand.
我明白了
You can head back now.
你先回去吧
Thank you.
谢谢你
I'll lock the door for you.
门给你锁上了
How about it?
怎么样
Am I right?
我说的准吧
Gu Chen and Xiao Yuhe
顾晨和肖宇河
both like you.
全都喜欢你
What do you think?
你怎么想的
I don't know.
我不知道
Do you like Gu Chen?
那你喜欢顾晨吗
No.
不喜欢
How about Xiao Yuhe?
那你喜欢肖宇河
You still like him?
你还喜欢他呀
At the beginning,
其实最开始
I just thought he's handsome.
我就是觉得他帅
Hotheadedly,
头脑一热
I confessed my feelings to him.
就跟他表白了
After the love experiment
恋爱实验之后
I felt exasperated.
我就好生气啊
I made up my mind
自己下定决心
never to make a fool of myself again,
再也不要自作多情了
and never to have anything to do
也不要跟这个人
with this person again.
有半点关系
But then a lot of things happened,
但是后来发生很多事情
and I got to know
让我看到了一个
a different aspect of him.
不一样的他
Then I
然后我就
truly fell in love with him.
真的喜欢上他
He even treated me very well,
他甚至对我也很好
which made me feel that
让我觉得
maybe he,
他可能
more or less,
多少
also has a little bit of
也有那么一点点
a crush on me.
喜欢我吧
It turned out that it's my own wishful thinking again.
然后我又一厢情愿了
I was wrong again.
我又错了
He always makes me think
他就总让我觉得
that I'm a fool.
自己是一个很蠢的人
that I'm not a person who's worth
不是一个值得
being loved.
被人爱的人
I hate to feel this way.
我很讨厌这种感觉
You're wrong.
不是啊
Why do you always think for him?
你为什么总要为他想呢
You cannot deny yourself
你不能因为别人
just because of someone else.
就否定你自己呀
Right?
对不对
No matter what Xiao Yuhe thinks,
不管肖宇河怎么想
we all like you,
我们大家都很喜欢你呀
and you are not a fool at all.
你一点也不蠢
There, there.
好了好了
Well,
那
what about Gu Chen?
顾晨那边你打算怎么样
You're gonna make it clear to him?
去跟他说清楚啊
I'll make it clear to him.
我去跟他说清楚
OK.
好
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Gu Chen.
顾晨
I bought you bubble tea.
给你买了奶茶
It's your favorite flavor.
你最爱喝的口味
Thank you.
谢谢
Why don't you look at the screen?
你倒是看屏幕啊
What's worth looking at?
有啥好看的
The drone. Where's the drone?
飞机呢 飞机
Take a look, are these two
你看这是不是
Su Chengcheng and Gu Chen?
苏澄澄和顾晨啊
I finally understand.
我算是明白了
I said a lot last time
我上次跟你说了那么多
and nothing registered with you.
你是一个字也没听进去
Xiao Yuhe.
肖宇河
It's not that I'm against you
我不是阻止你呀
participating in the competition,
去参加比赛
I'm not a...
我也不是
ruthless person either.
一个不近人情的人
I also grew up...
我也是从
from your age.
你这个年纪过来的
I understand the passion
我了解你这个年纪的
young people at your age possess
年轻人想干一件事情的
when they want to do something.
那种热情
But it really
但是现在时机啊
is not the right time.
是真的不成熟
What happened to you
前些年
years ago
你那个事情
was just barely suppressed,
好不容易才压下去
and you want to do it again.
你现在又要干
Aren't you deliberately
你不是成心
putting yourself in danger?
往风口浪尖上撞吗
Right?
对不对
Moreover,
而且
our laboratory is
咱们实验室的压力呀
under great pressure as well.
现在也很大
A lot of pairs of eyes
那么多双眼睛
are on us.
都盯着呢
Our research paper
咱们的论文
was rejected, again.
又被退回来了
If it continues this way,
要再这么发展下去
our laboratory's funding
所有的资金
will be withdrawn entirely.
那就从实验室撤走了
Your phone just won't stop, right?
你看看你那个手机
It's been buzzing the entire time.
嗡嗡嗡的
Take a look at it.
你看看吧
See.
你看
Are these two Chengcheng
这是不是澄澄师妹
and Gu Chen?
和顾晨
They are at the garden,
他们在小花园
talking and laughing all by themselves.
孤男寡女有说有笑
Are you sure you are not going to take a look?
你确定不过去看看吗
You can leave. Just go.
你走吧 你走吧
Please take good care of
你把你自己事情
your own business.
处理好吧
I see that
我看呀
our laboratory
我这个实验室啊
really can't count on you.
我真指不上你
Prof. Du,
杜老师
please do not worry,
您放心
I'll put my heart
这个项目
in this project.
我一定会好好做
But I have my own insistence.
但我有我自己的坚持
I asked you to come here today
今天叫你来呢
is mainly because of
主要是有件事情
one thing I wanted to tell you.
想告诉你
-I like Senior Xixi... -I have a crush on someone else.
我喜欢西溪师姐
What did you say?
你说什么
You like Senior Xixi?
你喜欢西溪师姐
You know about how Senior Xixi is.
西溪师姐你也知道
She's not a person who likes
她平常都
to socialize,
不怎么跟人接触
so it's even harder to chase after her.
更不要说追她了
I've never told her,
我一直都没有告诉过她
but
但是
you are in the same group
现在你跟她
as her,
在一个组里面
so, I want to...
所以 我想
I got it.
我懂了
Thanks.
那谢谢了
Are you heading back to the dorm?
你要回宿舍吗
I'm going to the library,
我正好去图书馆
I can give you a lift.
我可以捎你一段
I'm good.
不用
I'll wait here for...
我在这儿等
I mean,
不是
I have an appointment with someone.
我跟人约好了
I have something else to do later.
一会儿还有点事
Well,
那个
I'll wait here a bit,
我在这儿等一会儿
you go ahead.
你先回去吧
OK, then bye.
行 那我走了
Gu Chen,
顾晨
why did you
你朋友圈
block me on Moments?
为什么屏蔽我呀
Why did I block you?
屏蔽你
I didn't.
没有啊
You did.
有啊
Tell me which post?
你说说哪一条啊
The one with a quotation from Shen Congwen.
就是 沈从文的那条
Here's the thing.
是这样的
When I posted something on my Moments,
我发朋友圈
my relatives always
总会有亲戚过来
asked questions and it's annoying,
问东问西的很烦
so I moved them
所以我就把亲戚们
into a group and blocked them.
拉了一个组屏蔽掉
M-My aunt's also named Su Chengcheng,
我 我二姨也叫苏澄澄
and I might have made a mistake.
我 好像拉错了
Take a look. Take a look.
你看你看
It's true, see?
真的你看
My aunt really is named Su Chengcheng.
我二姨真的叫苏澄澄
My aunt's name is Su Chengcheng.
我二姨叫苏澄澄
Fine, you win.
我真是服气
Hurry up and unblock me.
你赶紧给我拉出来
I know. I know.
我知道了知道了
OK.
好
I'm removing you from the group right now.
我现在就给你拉回来
-Later, aunt. -Off you go.
我走了 二姨
-Go. Bye. -I'm leaving.
走吧 再见
Bye. Bye.
再见再见
See you.
再见
I almost made a fool of myself again.
差点又自作多情了
That's a close call.
好险
Look.
你快看快看
What a tragedy.
真惨
Can you stop following me?
能别跟着我吗
I'll send you back.
我送你回去
You're here to watch me make a fool of myself, right?
你来就是看我出丑的吧
Then you can watch it all you want.
你看吧
Are you happy?
开心了吗
Dry yourself with this.
擦擦吧
Your hair's all wet.
头发都湿了
Who asked you to pity me?
谁让你可怜我了
Who asked you to mind my business?
谁让你管我了
Who asked you to be
谁让你假惺惺的
a hypocrite?
在这儿做好人啊
Who asked you to transfer me
谁让你让我去
to Senior Xixi's group?
西溪师姐那儿
Who asked you to let me stay in the lab?
谁让你让我留在实验室
Why are you being so unreasonable
你怎么这么莫名其妙
and annoying?
这么让人烦呀
I'm not wearing your clothes.
我不穿你衣服
It's...
这是
the one I bought for him.
我给他买的那件
So he didn't throw it away.
原来他没有扔
Put this on
穿好
and hurry back.
赶紧回去
Don't catch a cold.
别着凉了
Drink something warm.
喝点热的
It's none of your business.
不用你管
Drink it.
喝呀
What are you gonna do this time?
你又干吗
Drink my sorrows away.
借酒消愁
Cheers, my friend.
举杯吧朋友
Bring up your glasses.
举起你们的杯子来
Friends.
朋友们
Youth is brief.
青春短暂
Let's have another bottle again.
让我们再来一瓶
Su Chengcheng.
苏澄澄
The gate is over there.
大门在那边
We should head back now.
我们得回去了
Where did I go?
我去哪儿了
I'm at home.
我到我家了
I'm at home and I'm gonna sleep.
我到家了我要睡觉了
You're drunk.
你喝醉了
Let me take you back.
我送你回去
Nope.
我不要
If you don't head back now,
你再不回去
the dorm's gonna close.
宿舍就关门了
Xiao Yuhe,
肖宇河
do you know how much
你知道我为你
I've devoted to you?
付出了多少吗
Because of you,
我为了你啊
I spent the money
我把我
I had saved up for an electric bicycle.
买电动车的钱都给花了
Do you know how hard it is
你知道我攒那钱
for me to save up that amount of money?
有多难吗
I saved for over six months.
我攒了大半年呢
Do you know how many
你知道我填了
surveys I completed,
多少调查问卷
and how many times I became the practice partner with someone
陪练了多少次
to save up that small amount of money?
才挣的那点钱吗
Don't cry.
你别哭啊
Really, I worked so hard.
真的 我好辛苦啊
I worked hard to buy you a piece of clothing,
我挣钱给你买件衣服
and you threw it away.
你把它扔了
What are you laughing about?
你笑什么
Am I ridiculous?
我好笑吗
No.
没有
OK, you're drunk.
行行行 你喝醉了
I'll talk to you tomorrow.
我明天再跟你说
Don't say tomorrow to me.
不要跟我说明天
I don't want to hear it.
我不想说明天
Tomorrow I need to
明天我还要
ride my bicycle.
骑我的自行车
The chain of my bicycle
我那个自行车
always falls off.
它老掉链子
I have to place it back in place everyday.
我就天天给它安车链子
My hands are permeated with the smell of engine oil.
安得我手上都是机油味
Really. They still stink
真的 现在还有呢
with engine oil.
都是机油味
Have a sniff.
你闻闻呀
Really.
真的
Don't cry.
别哭别哭
My hands smell like engine oil.
都是机油味
OK, OK. Let's walk normally.
行行行 好好走
Watch your step.
别摔了
I'm not gonna fall over.
我才不会摔呢
I'm good at walking.
我走得可好了
Watch me.
我给你走一个啊
Am I good at walking?
走得好吧
Yes, not only walking,
是 不光路走得好
you are good at everything,
你哪儿哪儿都好
OK?
行吗
What am I good at?
我都哪儿好啊
Why so sudden?
这么突然吗
Let me think.
想一想啊
You
你
have good skills in execution and action.
执行能力强行动能力好
I've learned how to catch lab rats.
我都学会抓小鼠了
That's not what I mean.
我不是这意思
You are happy every day.
你每天都很开心啊
You are always in a good mood, right?
心情好 对吧
What else? Crying all day?
那要不然呢 天天哭
How about this?
那这样
Well,
你呢
Jianming likes you,
建明喜欢你
which means you are a good person.
证明你人好
What's the point of Jianming liking me?
建明喜欢我有啥用啊
You don't like me.
你也不喜欢我
Who says I don't like you?
谁说我不喜欢你
Let's go.
走啦
We're here.
到了
You should hurry up and get upstairs.
赶紧上去吧
It's almost time for the curfew.
不然门禁时间就到了
What for?
凭什么啊
Why do I have to do
凭什么你让我干什么
whatever you said?
就干什么呀
Why do I have to listen to you?
凭什么听你的呀
You are drunk. Get upstairs already.
你喝多了 快上去吧
Lemme tell you something, Xiao Yuhe.
肖宇河我告诉你
Don't you think you can do whatever you like to me
你不要仗着我喜欢你
just because I have a crush on you.
就可以对我为所欲为啊
Listen,
我告诉你
I was over you a long time ago,
我早不喜欢你了
to tell you the truth.
我跟你说实话吧
To me,
你对我来说
you are like this.
就像这个
The air.
空气
Do you understand, the air?
空气你知道吗
Like a bottle of air.
就像一瓶空气
That's enough.
差不多了吧
Are your roommates upstairs?
你室友在不在
How about asking them to pick you up?
要不让她们下来接你
You don't believe me, do you?
你不信是吧
I'll prove it to you!
你不信我证明给你看呀
See?
你看
Even if I'm this close to you,
我就算离你这么近
I'm...
我都
Am I blushing?
我是不是脸红了
There are many reasons to cause a blushing face.
脸红的原因有很多的
Blushing...
脸红
The causes of blushing
会造成脸红的原因
are plenty.
有很多种
A person with high blood pressure
患有高血压的人
will have an enlarged heart
会因为心脏扩大
and increased myocardial contraction rate,
心肌收缩率增加
causing...
造成
Blood vessels in the head to expand and become congested.
头部血管扩张充血
Yes.
对
Blood vessel dilation in the brain
还有脑部血管扩张
can also cause blushing.
导致脸红
In addition,
还有
menopausal women
更年期的妇女
also blush
因为体内雌激素少了
because of the decrease in estrogen.
她也会脸红的
So it cannot prove that I have a crush on you.
所以不能证明我喜欢你
Let me try again.
我要再试一次
See?
你看
Even if I hug you like this,
我就算这么抱着你
I also...
我也
My heart is racing.
我心跳好快啊
There are various causes
造成心跳快的原因
of the acceleration of heart rate.
有很多种
Intense exercise,
剧烈运动之后
excessive mental stress,
精神过度紧张
and hyperthyroidism
甲状腺机能亢进
can all result in heart racing.
都会让心跳过快
So it's not because
所以我也不是
I have a crush on you.
因为喜欢你
Don't overthink it.
不要想多了
You don't believe me?
不信啊
No,
不行
I can't do this.
我不能这样